publicis sapient

Associate Software Development Engineer 2

SUMMARY

Shagun Bandi is an Associate Software Development Engineer II at Publicis Sapient. He is currently working in the Bangalore Office. He had an intensive 12-week training program where he learnt about full-stack development, starting from HTML, CSS, JavaScript to Database technologies like Mongo and SQL. He also worked on Backend and Middleware technologies like Springboot and Node. He worked on an internal project for Sapient, contributing in Full Stack Development as well as DevOps. Currently he is aligned with Lloyds Banking Group working with API Enablers, Tools and Federation Team, working as a software developer. His current project is an automation tool that allows value stream developers to accelerate and streamline their API journey.

He has gained hand on experience with tools like NodeJs and Springboot for backend and middleware development, React and Gatsby for client side development, Kubernetes, Docker, GCP, Azure, Istio, Jenkins and OAuth2 for DevOps. He has also worked with MySQL and MongoDB for database management.

Shagun Bandi has acquired experience in software engineering and web technologies that involve technologies like Java, Python, Swift, Django, Android, etc through summer internships he has done in the past years. He has worked as a Backend Developer at Finbox were he worked on Python and Django and devised various algorithms for the company. Also in his pre-final year, he worked as Software Developer at Toppr were he worked on full-stack development of an android application. He used Django for backend development and java on the android studio for frontend development.

Shagun has also won various awards including SBI National Hackathon and certifications for Java and Data Analysis from MOOC platforms. He has completed various projects of his own including Home Automation, Dog-Vision, Social-Network which are available at his Github page.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Publicis Sapient, July 2019 To Present

Developer - API Enabler (Tools and Federation Team), Lloyds Bank Group

Aim of the project is to develop flash, an automation tool that allows the value stream developer to accelerate and streamline their API journey. The tool basically allows the value streams to design, secure, validate, deploy and test APIs on bank approved API Management platforms including Azure API Management and IBM API Connect with minimal support whilst providing time-to-market and conformance to published API standards.





- 1. Worked on adding a new stage for displaying the versions of newly deployed artefacts on Azure Pipeline
- 2. Migrating the code from earlier version of flash to the current one
- 3. Adding new features on the documentation page, like adding more custom tags
- 4. Fixing the bugs in already existing code, which were causing issues to the value stream developer.
- 5. End to end testing of the application on MacOS and Windows VM
- 6. Component and Unit testing of the application
- 7. Documenting the changes using Gastby

Skills/Domain: NodeJS, Azure, Cucumber, Gatsby, Git

Associate Software Development Engineering II - Payment as a Platform

The aim of the project is to create Payment as a Platform. We want to create a unified payment system which can be plugged into any product for a secure payment.

- 1. Design the System Architecture for the Application.
- 2. Setup Kubernetes environment and Jenkins Pipeline for one click deployment of the application on GCP.
- 3. Add Istio and Auth0 security in the application, securing all the microservices.
- 4. Writing Microservices with Springboot.

Skills/Domain: GCP, Kubernetes, Docker, Istio, Auth0, Jenkins, React, Springboot

Associate Software Development Engineer II - Training

Learning the Basics of full-stack development and creating a web application named Marcus. Marcus is basically a banking application for Goldman Sachs whose aim is to have a 100% online banking system.

- 1. Writing few microservices for the application.
- 2. Writing few components for the front-end of the application.
- 3. Hosting the website on AWS.
- 4. Wrote various integration and performance tests for the application.
- 5. Worked as a Team Lead, organizing and allotting work to the team. Also deciding upon the sprint.

Skills/Domain: HTML,CSS,JavaScript,React,Node,Mongo,Java,AWS,Docker





IIT Kharagpur, August 2015 To April 2019

Researcher - App development for real-time irrigation scheduling

Provide the farmer with a basic application notifying him about the irrigation requirements of the crop.

- 1. A BTP project to build crop growth requirements model taking into account various realtime changes near the field.
- 2. Developing a Django Server to expose the API calculated from the initial data provided by the farmer.
- 3. Developing an android app with basic UI for the farmer to register the user, his farm details and notifying him about irrigation details.

Skills/Domain: Python, Django, MySQL, API, Java, Android

Wed Developer - Social Network

Develop a fully functional social networking website

- 1. To develop a Django based social network website that can send/receive friend requests, create posts, comment threads, insert images, etc.
- 2. Developed API endpoints for all the above actions, so as to easily use it on any platform.

Skills/Domain: Django, Python, MySQL, Django REST framework

Java Developer - Text Editor

Develop a GUI Text-Editor with functionalities like spell-checker, autocomplete, MarkovText, WordPath

- 1. Develop the backend for all the above features.
- 2. Perform unit testing for all the features.

Skills/Domain: Java

Toppr, May 2018 To July 2018

Software Development Intern - Previous Year Questions





Applications to log in the user and provide with previous year question papers and NCERT solutions according to his search history.

- 1. Used SQL queries to get the required data from various sources and designed an efficient database using it.
- 2. Developed RESTful web services with JSON representation and hosted the service on Amazon Web Services.
- 3. Created 2 fully functional application for Android devices namely PaperPro & NCERTPro, using Java and uploaded it on Google Play Store.

Skills/Domain: Python, Django, MySQL, Flask, Django REST-Framework, Java, Android, Testing

Finbox, May 2017 To July 2017

Back-end Developer Intern - SMS Data Understanding

Develop API to get the user's financial statement from his SMS data.

- 1. Designed an algorithm that finds the user's Income, their expenditures, savings, and bank account statement and suggests a budget.
- 2. Developed backend for mobile SDK and was responsible for building the module for SMS data understanding using java.

Skills/Domain: Python, Dajngo, Flask, API, Pandas

EDUCATION:

B. Tech (Bachelors in Technology), Agricultural and Food Engineering: IIT Kharagpur, 2019

SKILLS:

Database MySQL, MongoDB

Data Analysis Pandas, Numpy, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit learn, Tensorflow

Programming

Languages

Java, Python, JavaScript, C, C++, Swift

DevOps Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Istio, GCP, Azure DevOps, APIM

Tools and Frameworks Springboot, ReactJS, NodeJS, Django, Firebase, Fabric,

Auth0, Cucumber

Associate Software Development Engineer 2



Web Designing HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material, Gatsby

ADDITIONAL DETAILS:

Certification/Trainings

Complete Machine Learning and Data Science: Zero to Mastery

Object Oriented Programming in Java (UC San Diego)

Awards

"Sapient-Rookie of the year" award who proved themselves to be impactful beyond their experience level.

Rewards_and_Recognitions : Core Value-Engaging with Openness

SBI National Hackathon

Links

GitHub account https://github.com/shagunbandi

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/shagunbandi/